When you finished the loading,
東西都裝好了以後
board on the ship in order and wait for the next instruction!
依次上竹葉扁舟待命
I'll go with you!
我也去！
Nibi, you are not elected.
尼比 你沒被選上
Remain here and protect Kicha and others.
留下來 保護好綺茶他們
I've had enough!
不要
Don't leave me alone!
我已經受夠被丟下了
Nibi-kun, thank you for your willing but...
尼比同志 很感謝你的意願 但是…
Shut up! Don't talk to me, you idiot vigilante!
別吵 該死的警備團給我閉嘴！
Calm down.
冷靜
Hey, haven't you heard anything?
喂 你們沒聽到什麼聲音嗎
There are sounds other than the sandstorm.
沙暴以外有什麼東西在響
What?
什麼
They are coming...
…來了
The enemies, they are right there!
敵人 就在我們附近！
Translator
翻
ssnake
譯
静寂よ　旋律よ　儚き印よ
ssnake
Silence and melody, and the transient lives of Shirushi
静寂よ　旋律よ　儚き印よ
Timing
時 間 軸
zwc1991
zwc1991
砂上にこの地に　生き続けたのなら
砂上にこの地に　生き続けたのなら
If you have been living on the land, on the sea of sand
如果是在這沙海之上  生活下去
罪を纏う世界から　鯨の歌を聴いた...
罪を纏う世界から　鯨の歌を聴いた…
In a sinned world, we have heard the whale's lied
在罪業重重的世界裡  我們曾側耳傾聽鯨魚的歌唱…
運命を　感情を　抱くべき子たちよ
運命を　感情を　抱くべき子たちよ
Our fate and our emotions, my beloved children
不論命運  還是感情  親愛的孩子們喲
さ  き
さ  き
その先へ　その未来へ
その先へ　その未来へ
Towards the future, go ahead
向著未來  向著前方
導かれたのなら
導かれたのなら
If you can be our guide
只要有你指引前路
幾千の声　空想の地へ
幾千の声　空想の地へ
Thousands of words, leaving for the fantasy lands
萬千寄語  向著空想的彼岸
舵を切って行こうとした
舵を切って行こうとした
Steering towards the opposite
相信信念調轉方向
バラード
バラード
幾千の声　砂の海の譚歌
幾千の声　砂の海の譚歌
Thousands of songs, they are the ballads of the sea of sand
萬千歡聲  是沙海的歌謠
F
雪 飄 工 作 室
L
雪 飄 工 作 室
That's Skulax!
是斯奇洛斯！
φάλαινα
φάλαινα
As planned, our ship is approaching the route of Fallaina.
根據預定計劃 本艦將接近法萊那巡航路線
Is that something endless?
這東西停不下來嗎
I don't know.
不知道
But it seems to be a meteorological phenomenon peculiar to this area.
據說是這一片海域獨特的氣象現象
It is said that the prehistoric relics under the sea caused this phenomenon.
有傳言說是因為深海裡長眠的史前遺物
καρχαρίας
καρχαρίας
όρκα
όρκα
Should we contact Orca-sama in the Karcharías,
要通報「卡魯哈利阿斯」的奧爾卡司令嗎
αράχνη
αράχνη
Commander Arakhne?
阿拉弗尼司令
...Nope
…不用
We don't need to confirm every tiny case with that guy.
這點小事不需要專門找那傢伙確認
Continue advance forward.
繼續前進
φάλαινα
φάλαινα
Land the Fallaina!
在「法萊那」靠岸
Yes sir, Skulax advance forward!
是 斯奇洛斯前進
...Advance...forward...
…前…進
The god of the heaven,
蒼穹之神啊
Thank you for being generous and give me such a wonderful friend!
多謝你賜予我
My friend! Crying and laughing as much as you can!
我的朋友啊 好好哭過笑過
Anger by me, and fear me!
憤怒過…害怕過
Then let me see
然後 讓我
the perfect face of your death!
見識一下至高的死相吧！
Everybody, start navigation!
各位 開始航行！
Nibi-kun, come with us!
尼比同志也一起來！
砂上の友よ
砂上の友よ
My friend on the sand.
沙海上的朋友啊
愛しき友よ
愛しき友よ
My dear friend.
我親愛的朋友啊
てのひら
てのひら
掌の砂を見よ
掌の砂を見よ
Please look at the sands on your hands.
請你看看零落掌心的飛沙
ここに幾億もの
ここに幾億もの
There are millions and thousands
那裡有成千上萬的
光あり
光あり
of lights.
光華
ひから
ひから
あなたが干涸び
あなたが干涸び
One day you will dry out.
你終將乾涸
ひから
ひから
あなたが干涸び
あなたが干涸び
One day you will dry out.
你終將乾涸
ひつぎ
ひつぎ
柩にその身を結わえられ
柩にその身を結わえられ
Your body will be tied inside a coffin.
你的身體終會繫身靈柩
結わえられ
結わえられ
inside a coffin.
繫身靈柩
いにしえ
いにしえ
古の深海の中
古の深海の中
Deep in the antique ocean,
在這悠久的深海之中
こぼ
こぼ
毀れども禁忌の園に
毀れども禁忌の園に
in the garden of ruins and sins,
在這壞滅而又禁忌的樂園裡
園に
園に
ruins and sins,
樂園裡
たっと
たっと
尊く生きん
尊く生きん
you continue to live with dignity.
尊貴地活下去
砂上の友よ
砂上の友よ
My friend on the sand
沙海上的朋友啊
愛しき友よ
愛しき友よ
My dear friend
我親愛的朋友啊
砂上の友よ
砂上の友よ
My friend on the sand
沙海上的朋友啊
愛しき友よ
愛しき友よ
My dear friend
我親愛的朋友啊
Start attacking!
開始攻擊！
Shoot!
射！
I've done it!
幹掉了！
Hurrah!
好棒〜好棒〜
Let's take their weapons!
我們去搶武器！
Go back, be quick!
快回去 快點！
Hurry up! Hurry!
快點 快點！
I fo~und you!
找～到了！
Get out! Play together with me!
快出來 陪我一起玩啊！
Suo-sama!
蘇澳哥哥
What's up?
怎麼了？
We picked this up!
我們撿到這個了
What's this?
這是…？
Please use it to defend yourself!
請用來防身！
Let's go pick something again!
我們再去撿一次！
Yeah!
嗯
Ah, wait...
啊 等等…
Suo-sama!
蘇澳哥哥！
What's wrong with you?
你怎麼了？
Are you OK, Suo-sama?
沒事吧 蘇澳哥哥
Great, you've done it!
好樣的～ 爬上來辛苦了
Here's the entrance!
這是入口
This is Skulax...
這就是斯奇洛斯…
It's made of mud...?
…是泥做的嗎…？
Both Skulux and the ship of Lykos, and also the mud whale...
不管是斯奇洛斯還是黎可斯那艘船… 還有泥鯨…
They have the same smell.
都是一樣的味道…
I remembered,
對了 在黎可斯的船上看到的帝國人的心靈
and the world Neli showed me,
還有奈莉給我看的世界
have made me feeling nostalgic.
都是同樣的讓人懷念
However, why should we...
可是 為什麼我們卻…
Chakuro!
查克羅！
Chakuro, take a prone!
查克羅 趴下！
Let's go!
我們上
Yeah!
噢！
Sir.
報告
Our guards encountered some intruders in the underground passage.
警備兵在地下通道裡遇到了侵入者
They seems to be the residents of Fallaina.
相信是法萊那的住民
They've come as we expected.
果然來了呢
Their aim should be...
他們的目的恐怕…
νοῦς
νοῦς
The Nous.
是魂形吧
Yes.
是的
Have you seen the younger sister of the general commander Orca?
奧爾卡總司令的妹妹呢？
She is confirmed to be with the enemies.
已確認她與敵軍同行
It seems that she is guiding them to the Room of Nous.
正帶領他們前往「魂形之室」
Let's capture her,
抓起來
according to the order of the general commander Orca.
奧爾卡總司令也下過命令了
We should kill them as soon as possible,
不是該立刻幹掉他們嗎
including Orca's sister.
奧爾卡的妹妹也給我幹掉
Bu...But...
可…可是這…
Concentrate!
別發呆
It's not the mud whale here!
這裡可不是泥鯨
Answer my question, intruder!
侵入者 回答我的問題
Who are you?
你的真身是什麼？
Answer me!
回答我
Are you
你就是…
φάλαινα
φάλαινα
δαίμονας
δαίμονας
the Daímonas of Fallaina?
「法萊那的惡靈」吧
You're so strong!
好厲害啊！
But don't work too hard, you'll exhaust out, Pony-kun!
不過別太拚了 當心一會沒勁了 小尾巴！
My lads of the vigilante group, let's go!
警備團的各位同志 咱們上！
Let us go with them.
我們也過去吧
We can not live through unless we hurt others.
要想活下去就要傷害他人…
If so...
這也未免…
Then it would be too painful to live.
太過殘忍
However, I did not want to lose anyone from the mud whale...
但是 我不想失去任何一位泥鯨的伙伴
again...
不想再一次…
Chakky!
查奇！
Nice cover!
防得漂亮！
We can no longer call you the destroyer!
這樣毀滅者的污名也得以昭雪了呢
Hurry up! More pursuers will come!
抓緊！ 還會有追兵的
Yeah!
噢！
It's not my misread,
果然不是我的錯覺
the people on the mudwhale,
泥鯨上的百姓
sentikinesis
thymia
have stronger thymia than the people of the empire.
情念力確實要比帝國的人強
What has happened?
發生什麼事了？
Suo-sama! The central tower...
蘇澳哥哥〜！ 中央塔被…
has been drilled a hole!
炸開了個洞…
And the enemies are entering!
敵人都進到裡面來了
...I will go there.
…我過去
Are you mad?
你在說什麼胡話
But!
可是！
The chief must stay in the safest place!
首長必須留在最安全的地方！
You are the support of everybody's mind!
因為你是大家心靈的支柱
If I'm the support of minds...
要是我是心靈的支柱…
Then it's the time I should go!
那此時此刻正需要我！
Ah, wait...
啊 等等…
You... Idiot!
真是… 笨蛋！
Run away, kids!
大家 快逃
The reinforcements will soon be here from the ground.
過一會下面就會有援軍過來
Hakuji-sama...
哈庫奇爺爺…
Move! Hurry up!
快 快點！
I will not allow you to hurt the kids!
絕對不允許你們傷害孩子們！
Leave, you demons!
快走開 你們這群惡魔！
Hukuji-sama!
哈庫奇爺爺！
Su...o...
蘇…澳
Don't talk! I will take you to the aid station now!
別說話 我這就送您去急救站
I was... trying to... sink the island...
讓…這個島…沉沒…這件事…
But... it's... wrong...
是…我…錯了…
I want...
我想…
to see... your future...
看到…你們的…未來…
Even... the world... hates you...
不管… 世界…是…多麼…恨著…你們…
I... love... the mud whale...
我是… 真心…愛著…
and you...
泥鯨…和…你們…
Sorry!
哎呀不好意思
Were you still talking?
打斷你們說話了
But I thought
不過啊 那個老爺爺
that old guy is already helpless!
怎麼看都已經不行了嘛～
Shut up.
請閉嘴…
What?
什麼？
Look who's talking?
態度這麼不可一世
Why are you so angry?
你生什麼氣呢
Hey, you wanna revenge that old guy?
喔 難不成要給老爺爺報仇？
Then draw your sword!
快拔劍啊
Hurry!
快點
I will never forgive you
我絕不允許任何人
for your insult to Hakuji-sama!
侮辱哈庫奇爺爺
That's good!
這就對了
Your eyes!
這個眼神
I'm loving it!
我最～喜歡了！
Hey, what's up?
喂 怎麼了啊～
Say it again!
再像剛才那樣不可一世地叫囂一次啊～
I don't like this.
怎麼搞的
Your eyes are looking like the doll's.
這洋娃娃一樣的眼神
I'm already tired of dolls!
傀儡娃娃們我早就看膩了
Cry more! Scream more!
給我多哭幾把叫幾下啊～
Every guy seems to be dead!
不管是誰都像死了一樣的
It's so boring! Hey!
一點意思也沒有 喂！
It's not me that is crazy!
不是我瘋狂
It's the world that is out of joint!
而是這個世界太瘋狂啊！
Yes, the time is out of joint.
沒錯 是世界太瘋狂了
What?
啊？
But as long as that boy is my boss,
不過這個小哥 姑且也是咱老大
could you stop please?
能請你住手嗎
And, you are...
然後啊 你啊…
as annoying as an fly! ♪
比蒼蠅還聒噪呢♪
...What?
…什麼？
Here!
這裡
νοῦς
νοῦς
σκύλος
σκύλος
Skulax the Nous is over there!
魂形·斯奇洛斯就在這裡面
φάλαινα
φάλαινα
But the same the Fallaina, we can't use thymia over there.
但和法萊那一樣 這裡面就不能用情念力了
Everybody has done it well and got here!
到這裡誰都沒有掉隊
Then we can finish our mission as we planned!
這樣一來就能夠和事先安排的一樣 順利完成任務
Oni-kun and you guys should hold the entrance with thymia.
歐尼同志你們用情念力守住入口
We are going to destroy the Nous with the guidance of Lykos!
我們由黎可斯帶路 幹掉魂形
OK?
行吧？
Got it!
了解了！
Lykos, be careful.
黎可斯…小心點
Hey, let's go!
來 我們走
They're the stained glass!
是玻璃畫啊
So beautiful...
好漂亮…
Yep...
是呢…
No!
哪有 在我看來
Hurry up, our hero!
趕緊走吧 英雄！
It hurts!
痛
Right, let's go!
好 趕緊走
Strange...
好奇怪…
How can we penetrate into the room of Nous so easily...
居然這麼簡單就侵入到魂形之室裡來了…
There is even no sign of pursuers...
也沒有一點追兵的動靜
Why...
為什麼…？
Wait!
等等
Tokusa, everyone!
托庫薩 各位！
Wait, Urumi!
等等 烏露米
Nibi, are you injured?
尼比 你受傷了嗎
Why didn't you tell us?
為什麼不說出來
How can I tell you as I'm the only one made a boob!
就我一個人搞砸了 怎麼說的出口啊
I forced you to take me here, it sucks if I become your passenger.
明明是我非要來的 還扯大家後腿 這可丟人了…
You Idio...
白痴…
It's from the room!
從房間裡面響起來的！
Oni!
歐尼！
You are injured, stay here!
你受傷了 給我待在這
Chakky!
查奇！
Is it fine, Ginshu?
沒事吧 銀淑？
Call me Miss Ginshu!
叫「姐姐」！
We can't leave it empty here, right?
這裡總不能一個人都不留吧？
I will not allow even an ant enter!
我誰都不會放過去的！
There are merely a few things,
我能夠記錄下來的…
I can write done in my records...
只是世間的些許
The worlds people saw at their ends...
人們臨死前所見到的世界…
The worlds reflected in their eyes...
在他們眼睛裡映射的世界
How can I...
我要
pass them down...
怎樣才能把它們傳述下去呢
The seventh section
第 七 節
I want to see your future
第 七 節
乾いた海の跡　望んで
乾いた海の跡　望んで
Staring into the trace of the dried sea
眺望昔日的大海
まだ見ぬ対岸を描く
まだ見ぬ対岸を描く
I will draw the other side I have never seen
描繪未知的彼岸
囚われの心のままなら
囚われの心のままなら
If you remain your heart in captivity
如果囚禁起心靈  一如過往
こんな傷みも知らずにいた
こんな傷みも知らずにいた
You may live without knowing the pain
又怎麼會經歷如此悲傷
美しい詞を告げたひと
美しい詞を告げたひと
The one who told the beautiful story
是誰講述起美好的希望
夜明けも待たずに
夜明けも待たずに
Can not wait for the dawn
讓我等不及黎明
果てのその先を泳ぐ
果てのその先を泳ぐ
Until beyond the end of world, I am swimming
向著天涯海角揚帆起航
虫の唄
虫の唄
Listen to the insects' song
徹夜蟲鳴
眠らず君と聞いた記憶
眠らず君と聞いた記憶
That night is our memory
回憶裡與你一起側耳傾聽
手を　ただ結んで
手を　ただ結んで
Just link hand in hand
只是雙手相牽
半色でも　遠い国でも
半色でも　遠い国でも
No matter it is twilight or a distant country
不論夕陽  還是遠方
短い一章に生まれた夢を
短い一章に生まれた夢を
Born in a short chapter
在這短暫蒼渺的一章裡
抱きしめに行こう
抱きしめに行こう
But let us go and embrace that dream
一起追逐夢想
The eighth section
第 八 節
You ought to disappear from this world
從 這 世 上